can you maintain your squad della
strength by not doing any squats
adenosine just doing hip thrusts like
[Music]
what's up guys welcome to Booty blog
number one basically every time I post a
blog I'm also gonna record a YouTube
video with me just raw uncut talking
about it and the link to the blog post
will be in the description if you want
to check that out this first one is on
an eight-week experiment I conducted on
myself performing just hip thrusts leg
extensions and Nordic ham crust and my
goal was to see can I maintain my squat
dentistry and can I maintain my leg mass
my leg blue mass without squatting or
devotee so basically as the years go by
I can't handle as much as about deadlift
for him and by him my last six months of
squatting has been hard on my knees you
know I get it to where it feels good and
then they heard again same with my low
back we've done this so I just decided
you know what what if I just discarded
them for a while and focused on other
lives interestingly I wasn't doing
anything that really straightened my
erectors much and so throughout these
eight weeks I was able to push my hip
thrust very very hard because I did them
twice a week I did four sets I did them
first in my program and I did them
either on the smith machine or the glute
driver where i was going really deep and
i felt that that would help retain some
squat demonstrate because i get that
deep hip extension strength so I said
PRS on my hip thrust I also said a lot
of pillows on my leg extensions I went
from doing 200 pounds for 15 reps to 240
pounds for 20 reps
so that's the whole step I could do the
stack for 20 reps and then my nordic ham
curls strength went up towards the end
of the eight weeks I was lowering myself
very slow all the way to the ground so
my strength on those lifts went up and I
think my gluts size increased a little
bit they felt a little bigger to me
but what about my squat another spring
well when I tested my one rep max after
the eight weeks I found that I was able
to do a deep squat with 405 now I think
I could have hit for 25 but I didn't
want any you know this isn't some
competition so I didn't want to try that
but I think I could have it for 25 in
there I sumo deadlift 565 but
interesting I hadn't done anything with
a wide stance for 8 weeks and I think I
could have probably pulled 585 if I
needed to and these were the same
numbers I was doing before the a week
experiment so this to show that I was
able to maintain all of my squad other
strength without even sweating and
editing and the best thing about it was
after the end of these eight weeks I was
a pain free my knees felt amazing my
little back felt amazing and I think
that's a big component of why my
strength didn't go down because after
when I was testing my lower max
after the experiment I had felt pain and
it felt good when you have pain and pain
inhibits muscle activation so you're not
gonna get be able to put your all into
it and it felt really good being another
push without any inhibition or you know
any bad signals from any of my body
parts now interestingly while I did my
squats until this I felt like I had
never done them before I was so awkward
and uncoordinated it felt like when I
first was learning the lifts but my
strength was still there so what did
this experiment teach me for me I can go
periods without doing the specific lifts
and still maintain a ton of my strength
and maybe you're in a similar situation
and you might want to try this out and
see you know instead of taking time
completely long ways in the gym or
pushing yourself through pain switch the
list switch to you know like a hip
thrust leg extension leg curl or Nordic
and see if the same holds true for you
that you're able to maybe increase your
glutes eyes a little bit and maintain
your strength while getting out of pain
now I had conducted an experiment a
couple years ago an eight-week
experiment using machines only
mostly the Smith machine and I found
during thought that a twig experience I
found that I was able to be slightly
build my squad strength my deadlift and
hit those break went down but my
strength went up by doing tons of Smith
machine squats and hack squats so that
was a big learning learning experience
for me as well and then I would like to
do another a week experiment in the
future where I just do single leg
exercises and see what effect that has
on my strength if I just do you know
lunges and split squads and step ups and
single I already ELLs and single I can
throw things like that what will that do
to my squat deadlift to be able to
strengthen so I hope you like these
little experiments I know they're just
an equals one but maybe some of you are
it's similar dispositions and you want
to test it on yourself let me know in
the comments section if you have any
questions and I'll be sure to answer
[Music]